(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T02:03:25.828559",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always cause you nothing but trouble, but...
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I always trouble you so much, but...
それでも隣にいてくれる
Even so, you stay by my side.
君のそばにずっと
I want to be by your side forever.
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words...
真面目な君には伝わらない
it won't get through to serious you.
頑丈なそのハートを
That sturdy heart of yours...
覗いてみたい
I want to peek inside.
融かしてみたい
I want to melt it.
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
At times like this, how about a magic spell like this?
何が出るかな？
I wonder what will come out?
やっちゃえ！
Let's do it!
せーの！
Ready, go!
あやふやだって
Even if it's uncertain...
いいの！いいの！
it's fine! It's fine!
witch one to pick
Which one to pick?
watch me do magic
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh my, a development beyond my imagination!
もう止められないのよ
I can't stop it anymore!
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
溢れる想いで空回り
My overflowing feelings are spinning out of control.
振りかけるhappyなイメージ
Sprinkling a happy image...
で振り回すfancyなマジック
to brandish fancy magic!
また君に
You'll lecture me...
くどくど言われちゃうけどほら
again, but look!
こんな day by day がいい
I love this day by day.
あの日から
Since that day...
falling in love with you
I fell in love with you.
変わらないから
Because it won't change...
ずっと only you
it's always only you.
だからほら
So look...
うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
掴めハッピーエンディング
Seize the happy ending!
いつまでも
Forever and ever...
隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep smiling by your side!
いつも仲間はずれで
Always left out...
ひとりぼっちの毎日
spending every day all alone.
そんな私の前に現れた君は
When you appeared in front of me like that...
同じ寂しさを抱えている
you were carrying the same loneliness.
とてもとても優しい人
A very, very kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
Though I still have many worries...
もう私も君もひとりじゃない
neither you nor I are alone anymore!
愛しくて愛しいこの日々が ずっと続きますように
I hope these lovely, precious days will continue forever.
3 2 1 とばせ
3, 2, 1, let's fly!
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image
とびきりのファンシーなマジック
An extraordinary, fancy magic
また君に くどくど言われそうだけど
It seems like you'll nag me again, but...
そんなの take care take heart
...just take care, take heart!
あの日から falling love with you
Since that day, I'm falling in love with you.
気づいてほしいの love with you
I want you to notice, in love with you.
だからこそ うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
That's exactly why there's no time to dawdle.
次はどんなプランニング
What kind of planning next?
そしてまた今日もハプニング
And then another happening today.
明日はどんなおかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what kind of silly thing will happen tomorrow.
ずっと隣で見届けててね
Please keep watching over me right by my side.
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image
ファンシーなマジック
A fancy magic
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image
ファンシーなマジック
A fancy magic
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live stream today!
改めまして！もぐもぐーおかゆー！
Once again, Mogu Mogu Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆでーす！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
本日はこちら、ハッシュタグ「猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026」でいっぱい呟いてくださーい！
Please tweet a lot today using the hashtag #NekomataOkayuBirthdayFestival2026!
ライブ終わったあとすぐ見に行っちゃうんだからね！
Because I'll go check them out right after the live stream is over!
そして、みんな見て！今回のライブは「ヴィアードクッキー」というタイトルをつけました！
And look, everyone! I titled this live stream "Weird Cookies"!
「ヴィアード」っていうのは、奇妙っていう意味があるんだけど、
"Weird" has the meaning of being strange or odd,
なんで「ヴィアード」ってつけたのかなーとか考えながらライブを見てくれると嬉しいなって思っているよ！
but I'd be happy if you watched while thinking about why I chose "Weird"!
そして、見て！このステージ！
And look at this stage!
とっても可愛いでしょ？
It's super cute, right?
でも、可愛いだけじゃないんだよ！
But it's not just cute!
すごいね、曲によってガラッと雰囲気変わるように作っていただいたので、そこもね、注目してみてみてください！
It's amazing how they made it change atmosphere completely depending on the song, so keep an eye out for that too!
「えぇ！？」ってなるかもしれないね。
You might go, "Whoa!?"
そして！ゲストも！今回も盛りだくさんでございます！
And we also have a lot of guests this time!
ワクワク、ドキドキ、僕も今からなんか、ちゃんと振り付けとか歌とかいけるのかなーと思いつつも
I'm so excited and nervous. Even now, I'm wondering if I can pull off the dancing and singing...
ではね、みんなと楽しく自分の誕生日をお祝いできたらなと思っております！
But I hope we can all have fun celebrating my birthday together!
そして最後に！最後に！みんなに喜んでもらえるような告知、用意してあるので、
And finally, at the end, I have an announcement that I think will make you all happy,
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえればなと思っております！
so I hope you stay and enjoy until the very end!
ふふふ、次の曲行ってみようか！
Fufu, let's move on to the next song!
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙してるの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know that you're shedding tears all alone.
ビクンビクン 震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Trembling and shaking, your voice is completely leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ 効いてんの？
Just be honest. It's already been exposed, so just say it. Is it working?
普通 普通 恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ むふっ
Is it normal, normal to be embarrassed? Everyone is just hiding it. Mufu!
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙してるの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know that you're shedding tears all alone.
グスングスン 凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and depressed, singing solitary karaoke in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース
We're on this together until morning comes.
もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Cry some more, I'll catch you no matter how many times it takes.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you. Shake, shake with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたいねえいいでしょ？
If you don't cry, I'll wither. I want to be wet. Hey, is it okay?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば わぁ
I'm telling you, I want to lick it up and drink it dry. Wow!
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
頼り散らして シックラブなんて最高ね
Lean on me completely. Sick love is just the best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ 君の痛い感じていたいねえいいでしょ？
If you don't share, I want to feel your pain. Hey, is it okay?
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば わぁ
I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you. Wow!
見たい見たい見たい見たい... 君の中
I want to see, see, see, see... inside of you.
見たい 見たい 見たい...
I want to see, want to see, want to see...
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君が一人悔しがってんの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're frustrated all by yourself.
ズキュン ズキュン 高まるじゃん 君を推すことはやめない
Ba-thump, ba-thump, it gets me so excited! I won't stop supporting you.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君はできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're capable.
辛い時は 弱い位で丁度いい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When times are tough, being a little weak is just fine. I still love you regardless.
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ いつだって 会いに参上
Mwah! Please, I want you. Call my name, I'll show up anytime.
君はひとりだ だから歌う ひとりじゃない もういいでしょう
You are alone, so I'll sing. You're not alone anymore, isn't that right?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだっ たっ たってば
Solo play is over, I'm telling you!
きみが病めるときも あたし側にいるわ いつも見守っているわ
Even when you are sick, I will be by your side. I am always watching over you.
そうよ 怖くないのよ
That's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you.
慰めさせてよ shake shake 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you with my talent for love, shake shake!
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 触れていたい ねえいいでしょう
If you don't cry, I will wither. I want to touch you, is that okay?
涙拭って 飲み干したいんだっ たっ たってば
I want to wipe away your tears and drink them up, I'm telling you!
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの 頼り散らしてよ shake up なんて最高ね
Mwah! Please, I want you. Lean on me completely, shake up! It's so wonderful.
分けてくれなきゃ 君の痛い
If you don't share it, your pain...
感じてたい 寄り添ってたい
...I want to feel it, I want to be close to you.
吸い取って 救いたいんだっ たっ たってば
I want to suck it out and save you, I'm telling you!
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙知ってるの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you shed tears all by yourself.
グスングスン へこんでさ 弱音吐いて in the night
Shedding tears, feeling down, and whining in the night.
朝が来るまでいっそもっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
You might as well cry even more until morning comes. I will accept you over and over again.
もう我慢しないで出して たっ たってば
Don't hold it back anymore, let it out, I'm telling you!
そう
Yes.
デビルじゃないもん
[Title: Devil Ja Nai Mon]
はなまるの優等生
A perfect score model student,
今宵も自分と密会です
holding a secret meeting with myself again tonight.
しんどいわ しんどいわ
It's so tough, it's so tough.
ずらりずらりご開帳
Lining them up for a grand reveal.
本当は劣等生
But in truth, a failing student,
私は私に崇拝です
worshipping only myself.
しんどいわ しんどいわ
It's so tough, it's so tough.
もう嫌嫌 絶交
I've had enough, let's break it off!
心配無用 心配無用
No need to worry, no need to worry.
これは笑えるジョークさ
This is just a funny joke.
新米もん 老大もん
Newbies and veterans alike,
みんなで歌えるポップソング
a pop song everyone can sing.
まあまあ そう焦るなよ
There, there, don't rush so much.
ただの紙切れですよ<,s:
It's just a piece of paper.
いいから早く白状せや
Enough already, confess quickly!
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほど優しくないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil! I'm not as kind as a demon.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
I died, I died... I just want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら
But if you still fall for it,
それでも恋しちゃうなら
and if you still fall in love,
死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェル エンジェル
I died, I died... Angel, angel.
悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Bad news, bad news, bad news, bad news!
汚いね
How dirty.
飛べないね
You can't fly, can you?
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I died, I died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel until my demise.
あくまで天使調 最強じゃん
Ultimately, acting like an angel is the best, right?
切り取って 名言の 悪意
Cutting out and showcasing the malice in famous quotes.
夢叶って 奪って さらり
Dreams come true, then are smoothly stolen away.
中毒性の高い文脈に罠を張るんだな
Setting a trap within highly addictive contexts.
魂抜かれちゃって やんね やんね
Having my soul drained out, no way, no way!
光り輝く輪っかで この首が締まってく
This glowing halo is tightening around my neck.
嘘つきは許してくれんの？ 言えない SOS
Will you forgive a liar? I can't say SOS.
白いペンキ塗りましょう 成り切ってしまいましょう
Let's paint ourselves white and act the part completely.
嘘つきは楽になる ほらやっちゃって
Lying makes things easier, come on, just do it!
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil!
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I died, I died...
それでも穿っちゃうけど それでも嫌っちゃうけど
But even if I pry into it, even if I end up hating it,
成り切って笑顔で エンジェル エンジェル
I'll play the part with a smile, angel, angel.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほど優しくないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil! I'm not as kind as a demon.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
I died, I died... I just want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら
But if you still fall for it,
それでも恋しちゃうなら
and if you still fall in love,
死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェル エンジェル
I died, I died... Angel, angel.
悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Bad news, bad news, bad news, bad news!
汚いね
How dirty.
飛べないね
You can't fly, can you?
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I died, I died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel until my demise.
悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Bad news, bad news, bad news, bad news!
醜いね
How ugly.
映えないね
How un-photogenic.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm really not a devil.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I died, I died.
本当の悪魔になっても プレイング
Even if I become a real demon, I'll keep playing.
あくまで天使調 最強じゃん
Ultimately, acting like an angel is the best, right?
ずうっといっしょ！
[Title: Together Forever!]
充電器を貸して！
Lend me your charger!
またあなたのせいで あたし、HP減った
Because of you, my HP decreased again.
終電見逃して！
Miss the last train!
またあたしのせいで 帰れなくなった
Because of me, we can't go home again.
繋がっていようね
Let's stay connected.
繋がっていいよね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Since we're connected, dragging this into a war of attrition...
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル
We dragged each other down in our youth.
沈殿した思い出で ずうっといっしょ
With these settled memories, we'll be together forever!
参観日にだって
Even on parent visitation day,
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like nobody was looking at me.
散々シニカって
Adopting a thoroughly cynical attitude,
昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I tried not to expect anything from the daytime streets.
そうやって守った孤独さえ
Even the loneliness I protected that way
めちゃくちゃになった
was completely messed up.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly,
こんな顔だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I can't bring myself to care about a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together...
ささやかな幸せが
Our modest happiness...
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope it turns into an irreplaceable trauma.
はなればなれなんて
Being separated...
誰かが吐かせたバグだよね？
Is just a bug that someone let slip, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ<
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
q.大切なものって、なあに？
Q: What is the most precious thing?
a.今失くしたそれ
A: The thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've committed a mistake with me,
取り返しがつかないね
and there's no turning back.
健やかなるときも病める時も
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中でずうっといっしょ！
within our grotesque history, we'll be together forever!
もうちょっとふつうに
I wanted to feel sad
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
about sad things in a more normal way.
長調のチューンに感情委託して
I wanted to entrust my feelings to a major key tune
楽になりたかった
and put myself at ease.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please do your best to live your life."
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly,
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the beck and call of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで
Don't you dare think
あたしの目を盗んで
about going behind my back
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
to find happiness all on your own.
髪を乾かしてくれた night から
Ever since the night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I've been completely broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that has become stuck on your finger,
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている、最低だよ
it keeps flashing back over and over—it's the absolute worst.
一緒に居た時のほうが あたし可愛かったなぁ
I was much cuter back when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
q.大切なものって、なあに？
Q: What is the most precious thing?
a.今失くしたそれ
A: The thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've committed a mistake with me,
取り返しがつかないね
and there's no turning back.
健やかなるときも病める時も
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと眠っていても
even if you're sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢でずうっといっしょ！
we'll share the same nightmare, together forever!
愛♡スクリーム！
Ai ♡ Scream!
教えて！もっとあなたの事
Tell me! More about you,
Tell me, more, more, more! Tell me, more, more, more!
聞かせて！もっとあなたの声
Let me hear! More of your voice,
Let me hear, more, more! Let me hear, more, more!
こんなドキドキもう抑えきれない
I can't contain this throbbing excitement anymore!
All I need you, oh! All I need you!
友達は卒業 運命の私
Graduating from friends, destined for each other...
見つけてほしいの
I want you to find me!
勇気を出して
Gather your courage...
1, 2, chuu!
One, two, kiss!
見つめる作戦
Staring strategy!
3!
Three!
目が合えば
If our eyes meet...
4, 5!
Four, five!
止められない
Can't be stopped!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
この恋 この愛で
With this love, this affection,
Melty melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melty, melty, I'm melting away!
ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
届け！大好き
Reach him! I love you!
愛♡スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Ai ♡ Scream, Scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
愛♡スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Ai ♡ Scream, Scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
ルーナちゃん！
Luna-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミント！よりもあなた♡
More than chocolate mint... it's you! ♡
わためちゃん！
Watame-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりもあなた♡
More than strawberry flavor... it's you! ♡
おかゆちゃん！
Okayu-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあなた♡
More than cookies and cream... it's you! ♡
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好きアイスクリーム！
Of course we love ice cream!
止められない
Can't be stopped!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
この恋 この愛で
With this love, this affection,
Melty melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melty, melty, I'm melting away!
ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
届け！大好き
Reach him! I love you!
愛♡スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Ai ♡ Scream, Scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream! Ice cream!
愛♡スクリーム スクリーム
Ai ♡ Scream, Scream!
叫びましょう
Let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, Ice Cream!
お願い 見つけて my darling
Please find me, my darling
(my darling, my darling)
お願い 気づいて my darling
Please notice me, my darling
(my darling, my darling)
(one) 勇気を出して
(One) Gathering up my courage
(two) 近づく作戦
(Two) A strategy to get closer
(three) 手と手がお触れて
(Three) Our hands touching
(fall) 止められない
(Fall) I can't stop it
yeah, yeah, yeah, この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this romance, with this love
melt, melty, 溶けちゃうよ (ちゃうよ)
Melt, melty, I'm going to melt (Melt away)
ねぇ？ねぇ？ねぇ？気づいて "my darling"
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling
それは アナタ
That would be you
アイ愛、スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, scream, scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, Ice Cream!
アイ愛、スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, scream, scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, Ice Cream!
アイ愛、スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, scream, scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, Ice Cream!
アイ愛、スクリーム スクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, scream, scream, let's shout!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, Ice Cream!
la-la-la-la-love, love
La-la-la-la-la-love, love
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな
A magical, dreamlike...
ファンタジックな物語が
...fantastical story...
世界に感染 愉快に蔓延
...is infecting the world, running delightfully rampant.
待って、そんなの聞いてないってば
Wait, I've never heard of such a thing!
根本的に痛い 異常行動
Fundamentally painful abnormal behavior,
支える 枯れない 妄想量
holding back an amount of delusion that won't wither.
本能的に深い 破壊衝動
An instinctively deep destructive impulse,
照らす 確かな改造度
a definite granularity is illuminated.
恋の導火線
The fuse of love,
いざ、火を灯し
come on, let's take a match to it.
ひとつ、ここらで本調子
Now, it's the normal condition around here.
脳細胞に今
Now,
叩き込め
beat it into your brain cells,
わからないことだらけを
that there are so many things you don't understand.
あざとい、きわどい
Cunning, cruel...
笑わないで
...don't laugh at me.
いつも、いつも 誤魔化してば
You're always, always just deceiving me.
仮に
Hypothetically...
いらない、知らない、おだてないで
I don't need it, I don't know, don't try to sweet-talk me.
言えない、消えない、思い込め
An unspoken, unfading imagining...
愛の強制ミューティレーション
...'compulsive love mutilation!'
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな
A magical, dreamlike...
ファンタジックな物語が
...fantastical story...
世界に感染 愉快に蔓延
...is infecting the world, running delightfully rampant.
待って、こんなの聞いてない、ダーリン
Wait, have you never heard of such a thing, darling?
ベターな恋愛 エラーな展開
Better love, an erroneous plot twist,
だって、それじゃあつまらないでしょ
but isn't that just boring?
切り抜けて
Cut it out,
引きつけて
rip it out,
愛の顔面ストレート
a love punch to the face!
根本的にまずい 異常行動
Fundamentally unpleasant abnormal behavior,
支える いかれた情報量
holding back a maddening amount of information.
圧倒的に淡い 母性本能
An overwhelmingly faint maternal instinct,
暴く 飢えた奴隷根性
a starved servile nature is revealed.
愛の導火線
The fuse of love,
いざ、火をつけて
come on, let's take a match to it.
頭の中はアルデンテ
Is it al dente inside your head?
生細胞に今
Now,
流し込め
pour it into your living cells,
耐えがたいことだらけを
that there are so many things you can't endure.
冷たい触れ合い
A cold connection...
遊ばないで
...don't play games with me.
いつも、いつも 当てつけてば
You're always, always just insinuating things.
仮に
Hypothetically...
拙い、穿つ、ふざけないで
A clumsy question, don't screw with me.
言えない、消えない、思い込め
An unspoken, unfading imagining...
愛の眼球アイスピック
...'a love ice pick to the eye!'
好きな人の 好きな人ってだけで嫌い
I hate this person just because the person I like likes them.
都合の良い子 演じて一生 終わりたくないんだよ
I've been playing the total good girl all my life and I don't want to stop.
狂った未来に迎合 終わった抵抗
Going along with a crazy future, my resistance has ended.
いっそこのまま目を塞いで
Better to just keep your eyes closed.
切って爽快
Cutting refreshment,
喰らって崩壊
eating destruction,
知って後悔
knowing regret,
望んだ将来
the desired victory.
手を繋いで
Joining hands,
場を繋いで
joining places,
ファンタジックなすったもんだが
the fantastical commotion...
頭脳に感染 危険に発展
...infects our brains, progresses dangerously!
待って、こんなの聞いてない、ダーリン
Wait, have you never heard of such a thing, darling?
もう聞いてないってダーリン
You're not listening, darling.
ベターな恋愛
A conventional romance,
エラーな展開
an erroneous development.
だってそれじゃつまらないでしょ
But that would be boring, wouldn't it?
見つけて
Find me.
焼き付けて
Burn me into your mind.
溶けそうな三叉神経
My trigeminal nerve is about to melt.
狂いそうな感覚本能
My sensory instincts are going mad.
崩れそうな情を前に
In the face of feelings about to crumble,
愛のないレボリューション！
a loveless revolution!
ドキドキ めきめき 気流に
On this heart-pounding, rapidly rising current,
私は乗っている きっとね
I am riding, surely.
なんか言葉にできないこと
Things that somehow can't be put into words,
ちょっと心臓騒がすこと
things that make my heart flutter a little,
なんとなく今日を照らすこと
things that somehow brighten up today...
ちょっと好みの花見つけた
I found a flower that's a bit to my liking.
知らないフリばかり あってって
Always pretending not to know,
探したいものさえ 探せないよ
I can't even look for what I want to find.
ワクワクしたそのダイアリー
That exciting diary,
スランプにして放り出す なんて
throwing it away in a slump, or something...
ライライライライラ
Lai lai lai lai la
やるせないな どっち派？
How helpless, which side are you on?
WOW WOW WOW WOW
でもだけどきっと可能性あり
But still, there's surely a possibility.
気持ち風に浮遊して
Letting my feelings float on the wind.
ダッタッタ ちょっともっと いつかは飛び出たいな
Da-ta-ta, a little more, I want to jump out someday.
ドキドキ めきめき 気流に
On this heart-pounding, rapidly rising current,
私は乗っている きっとね
I am riding, surely.
イェイイェイイェイイェイ わからない物語にビビらないで
Yea yea yea yea, don't be scared of an unknown story.
きんら きんら 空に
Sparklingly in the sky,
世界が踊る
the world is dancing.
笑って イェイイェイイェイイェイ
Smile and yea yea yea yea,
縮こまってる時間はないな
there's no time to be shrinking back.
私を知りたい？
Do you want to know about me?
何もかもかもまだわからないないない
I still don't know anything at all-all-all.
私は見つけたい
I want to find it.
行ってきますを声にできたなら
If I could say "I'm off,"
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
maybe I've grown up just a little.
ちょっちょこちょっちょこ深呼吸
A quick, quick, deep breath.
優しくあるたびに失速
Slowing down every time I try to be kind.
つまんない筆跡は夢がない
Boring handwriting has no dreams.
ちょっと嫌いな自分見つけた
I found a part of myself I dislike a little.
暗い霧を終えて
Ending the dark fog,
雨に打たれて帰りたくなるの
being hit by the rain makes me want to go home.
ワクワクしたそのダイアリー
That exciting diary,
少し浮かれて走り出す なんて
starting to run in high spirits, or something...
まいやいやいやいやー
Mai ya i ya i ya i yaa
シャカリキで行こう
Let's go all out!
WOW WOW WOW WOW
お気に入りのアクセは失くしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory.
WOW WOW WOW WOW
まだ何もわかっちゃいないんだ
I still don't understand anything yet.
WOW WOW WOW WOW
避けて通っちゃ気持ち眠りたい
Avoiding it just makes me want to sleep.
あの星のように輝きたい WOW
I want to shine like that star, WOW!
ドキドキ めきめき 気流に
On this heart-pounding, rapidly rising current,
私は酔っている
I am carried away.
やっぱり イェイイェイイェイイェイ 答えのない世界で生きてるせいです
After all, yea yea yea yea, it's because we live in a world without answers.
みんな いいわ 優秀に 放っても変わんないし
Everyone is so excellent, even if left alone nothing changes.
叫んで イェイイェイイェイイェイ 私らしくたいて
Scream yea yea yea yea, let me shine in my own way!
ドキドキ めきめき 気流を
This heart-pounding, rapidly rising current,
乗り越えた先には
beyond overcoming it...
イェイイェイイェイイェイ わからない物語が待っている
Yea yea yea yea, an unknown story is waiting.
小さな勇気で何かを変えよう
With a little courage, let's change something.
あのね 大切な話があるんだ
You know, there is something important I want to tell you.
ここにない探しものがあるんだ
There's something I'm looking for that's not here.
だから旅に出ます
So, I'm going on a journey.
そのうち帰ります
I'll be back sometime.
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Maybe I've grown up just a little.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all meaningless.
Hey!
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all meaningless.
Hey!
夜が明ける
The night ends.
朝目覚める
I wake up in the morning.
首痛める
My neck hurts.
この身体に自分がいる
I exist in this body.
君と喋る
I talk to you.
飯を食べる
I eat food.
服を着てる
I wear clothes.
そのすべてが不気味である
All of that is eerie.
なんか変だ
It's somewhat strange.
変だ 変だ 変だ
Strange, strange, strange.
駅の改札通り抜ける
Passing through the station ticket gate.
こんな平和
This kind of peace.
平和 平和 平和
Peace, peace, peace.
当たり前でウケる
It's so ordinary it's hilarious.
猫の名前は なんとなくタマで
The cat's name is somehow Tama.
犬の名前は なんとなくポチだ
The dog's name is somehow Pochi.
犬の 名前は
The dog's name is
なんとなくポチだ
somehow Pochi.
世界は
The world...
...the world...
なんとなく終わりそうで
...seems like it's somehow ending.
存在を抱えたまま
While holding onto our existence,
夕焼けに溶けていくよ
we melt into the sunset.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も
There's no meaning to living, nor to working hard,
ない ない ない 無駄かもしれない
none, none, none, it might all be in vain.
千年後 何も残らないけど
In a thousand years, nothing will remain, but
それでも君と笑っていたい
even so, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
月が昇る
The moon rises,
星が光る
the stars shine,
虫が跳ねる
the bugs leap,
それを見てる
and we watch them.
あれ いつからここにいるんだっけ
Wait, since when have I been here?
いつまでここにいられるんだっけ
How much longer can I stay here?
何物にもなれないままで
Remaining as nobody,
化け物から逃げてるだけ
I'm just running away from monsters.
座敷牢でイメージを浮かべて
Conjuring up images in my room confinement,
ストップした思考は敵だらけ
my halted thoughts are filled with enemies.
太郎の名前は 今でも太郎で
Tarou's name is still Tarou,
次郎の名前は 今では花子だ
and Jirou's name is now Hanako.
時間は 時間は なんとなく通り過ぎて
Time, time, somehow passes by,
ゴミ溜めで埋もれたまま 星空を眺めてるよ
and buried in a trash heap, I gaze at the starry sky.
愛する意味も 恋する意味も
There's no meaning to loving, nor to falling in love,
ない ない ない 嘘かもしれない
none, none, none, it might all be a lie.
1＋1も よくわからん けど
I don't even really get what one plus one is, but
それでも君を守っていたい
even so, I still want to protect you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
それでも ぼくらは トンネルで息を止める
Even so, we hold our breath in tunnels.
折り紙で 鶴を折る
We fold paper cranes.
肉球を触る
We touch paw pads.
横断歩道の白い部分だけを踏む
We only step on the white stripes of crosswalks.
それでも ぼくらは 間違ったことをする
Even so, we still do wrong things,
正しいと思い込む
convinced that they are right.
頭いいから わかっていた
Because we're smart, we understood.
また 分かった気になっていたんだ
We were just pretending to understand again.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も
There's no meaning to living, nor to working hard,
ない ない ない
none, none, none,
ない ない ない ない ない ない ない ない ない
none, none, none, none, none, none, none, none, none...
それでも やるしかない
Even so, we just have to do it!
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も
There's no meaning to living, nor to working hard,
ない ない ない 無駄かもしれない
none, none, none, it might all be in vain.
千年後 何も残らないけど
In a thousand years, nothing will remain, but
それでも君と笑っていたい
even so, I still want to laugh with you.
夢を叶えても 悟り開いても
Even if we fulfill our dreams or reach enlightenment,
結局は孤独かもしれない
in the end, we might still be lonely.
おばけになっても 虚無に還っても
Even if we become ghosts or return to nothingness,
それでも君と笑っていたいな
even so, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明
Yes, we are all meaningless.
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Yes, because we are all meaningless.
そう 簡単な祈りだった
Yes, it was a simple prayer,
端から 段々と消える感嘆
with admiration gradually fading from the start.
今から 緞帳が上がるから
Since the stage curtain is about to rise now,
静かな 会場を後にさようなら
goodbye, as we leave the quiet venue behind.
言いかけていた事が 一つ消えてまた増えて
One thing I was about to say vanishes, then another is added,
背中に後ろめたさが 残る
leaving a sense of guilt lingering on my back.
従いたい心根を 吐き出さぬように込めて保存
Holding in my submissive feelings so I won't let them spill out,
胸の中が澱のように 濁る
the inside of my chest muddies like dregs.
受け止めたいことが 自分さえ抱えられず保存
Unable to even bear the things I want to accept myself,
持て余したそれを守っている
I'm protecting what has become too much to handle.
霞んだ声はからからに 喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
My hazy voice, parched and dry, burns and fills my throat,
何を言うべきかわからなくて保存
not knowing what I should say.
感じてたものが 遠く放たれていた
What I had been feeling was cast far away.
同じようで違うんだか違う
It seems the same, but somehow it's different.
何時まで行こうか 何処まで行けるのか
Until when shall we go? How far can we get?
定かじゃないなら何を想うのか
If nothing is certain, what should we think about?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら
If we are to drift apart, if we are to lose our way,
その度に何回も繋がれるように
so that we can connect again and again each time...
ここに居てくれるなら 離さずいれたら
If you would stay here with me, if I could hold on without letting go,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
I would be saved by a sensation that no one yet knows.
平穏とは 消耗を以て 代わりに成す
Tranquility is achieved in exchange for exhaustion,
実際は どうも変わりはなく
though in reality, nothing really seems to change.
享楽とは 嘘でならす
Pleasure is flattened by lies,
綻び
ripping at the seams.
ここを 出ていこうかと
Let's step out of here...
都合の良い願いを
...and whisper those convenient wishes,
同じように 同じように つぶやく
over and over again.
どこから 聞こうか
Where should we start listening?
何を見失うか
What are we going to lose?
定かじゃないから ここを動けない
Since nothing is certain, we cannot move from here.
僕らが 疲れるなら
If we get exhausted,
これ以上 ないなら
if there is nothing more than this,
その度に何回も 逃げ出せるように
let us be able to escape again and again.
心が 守れるように
To protect our hearts,
奪われないように
so they won't be stolen,
互いに 託して身体を預けてよ
let's trust each other and surrender our bodies.
ラルララルラ
La-lu-la, la-lu-la
君と泣く
To cry with you,
君と笑う
to laugh with you,
君と怒る
to be angry with you.
君と歌う
To sing with you,
君と踊る
to dance with you,
君と話す
to talk with you.
いつまで 続くのだろうと
How long will this go on?
同じように 同じように つぶやく
I whisper over and over again.
今は 忘れないよう
Now, so we won't forget,
刻まれた 空気を
this atmosphere carved into us.
これから何度 思い出すのだろう
How many times will we remember this?
僕らだけが
Only we...
僕らが 触れるなら
If we can touch,
僕らが 迷うなら
if we are to lose our way,
その度に 何回も 繋がれるように
let us be connected again and again.
ここに いてくれるなら
If you stay here for me,
離さず いられたら
if I can keep you close,
まだ誰の知らない
with a feeling
感覚で 僕の
that nobody knows yet,
生きてる全てを確かめて 正しくして
verify everything about my life and make it right.
Expected real
Very expected real
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) O child of worries,
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those who are not human,
(Be happy!) 弛まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Strive without faltering,
生きているんだし
after all, you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future,
カウンセリング やれやれ
it's time for counseling, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
Through all times and places, peace peace!
(Unhappy?)
(Unlucky?)
(Be happy!)
(Undead)
ねえねえ ねえねえ 何だか どうして
Hey, hey, hey, hey, somehow and for some reason
戦っているような そんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting a battle.
触れられない 触れたくもない
Untouchable, and I don't even want to touch
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
my past self, self, self, self.
もうとっくに死んでる
It has already been dead for a long time.
透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost,
幼気で 痛い 記憶の奥
deep inside innocent, painful memories.
残念? もう居ないのに
Disappointing? Even though it's no longer here.
あれ? そっちが良い? アイロニーね
Oh? Is that side better? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分?
Is it my current self that is being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label.
Yes! 要は コンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It seems like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ 離れない
Coiled around, it still won't let go.
在りし日の自分
The self of bygone days.
Undead
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself.
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive means to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be content.
幸せになろうとしない なんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to be happy is just cowardly.
この世 この世は 奇怪 奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は何が出るか
What will come out next?
蛇が出るか
Will it be a snake?
出会って 遭って やっと始まる物語
Encountering, facing, the story finally begins.
さあ人か怪物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
To change the subject, peace peace!
Past & future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
カカカットイン
C-c-cut-in!
なんだか どうして 未来になんぞ
Somehow, why is it that for the future,
何の希望も無い 期待出来ないような気がして
I feel like there's no hope, nothing to expect?
もう随分生きている
I've already lived for quite a while.
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with déjà vu and templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of any wonderful events.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Regrettable, the cause and effect of accumulated experience.
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
A hollowed-out myth and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want some stimulation.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて
Saying "I'm bored" or "I'm used to it"...
整っていくガイダンス
The guidance that is falling into place,
増えるコンプライアンス
and the increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
it feels like being covered by a lid.
吸い尽くして あれもこれもどれも 同じ味がする
Sucking it all dry, that, this, and everything tastes the same.
Undead
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself.
何時の世も 過去も 未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future are in this very moment.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your life with honest dedication.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
Undead
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet.
お前にお言っているんだ
I am talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ保存
Never give up on happiness; keep being human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ保存
Just being used to suffering and enduring it
死んでいるも同然
is no different from being dead.
屍のアンデッド
An undead corpse.
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) O child of worries,
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those who are not human,
(Be happy!) 弛まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Strive without faltering,
生きているんだし保存
after all, you are alive.
不幸に浸るも
Wallowing in misfortune,
幸せになるのも
or becoming happy,
そう全部全部 お前だ
yes, it's all up to you.
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Through all times and places, everything, peace peace!
Past & future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
人の在る所に 何時も憂い事
Wherever humans gather, there are always worries.
生き抜け この怪物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
ピースピース
Peace peace!
悪魔の踊り方 (作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ)
How to Dance with the Devil (Lyrics/Music: Tatsuya Kitani)
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った
"Emotions are useless no matter what," said the devil.
何もかも捨てちまえよ
"Just throw everything away!"
ああ、快、不快も喜怒哀楽さえも
Ah, pleasure and displeasure, even human emotions!
どうしようもない事実、ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
It's an inescapable truth; humans cannot escape from their end.
誰も抗えない欲望に従え
Obey the desires to which no one can resist.
思考を休めるな、脳みそを回せ
Do not rest your mind; put your brain into action.
「誰も お前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is watching you or anything."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる？
Why are you ashamed of becoming a little strange?
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を
I'll teach you a perfect but wrong way to dance,
教えてやるから
so I'll show you how.
いっせーので捨てちまえ、そんな命ならば
Ready, set, go! Throw it away if it's that kind of life.
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, millions of times.
どうしたってさ、空っぽの頭蓋骨だろ
After all, your skull is completely empty.
わかっているのかい
Do you understand?
感情なんていつなんどきでも邪魔だって悪魔は言った
"Emotions are a nuisance at any moment," said the devil.
「反論の余地などない」
"There is no room for objections."
ああ、人生に意味を与えておくれ
Ah, please give meaning to this life!
420でさえも救えない終焉があると知った
I knew there was an end from which not even 420 could save me.
誰も疑わない神様を疑え
Doubt the god that no one doubts.
思考を休めるな、脳みそを回せ
Do not rest your mind; put your brain into action.
「誰も お前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is watching you or anything."
躊躇っている数秒 of 無益さを知れ
Know the futility of your few seconds of hesitation.
お前らに完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you a perfect but wrong way to dance,
いっせーので捨てちまえ、そんな命ならば
so if it's this kind of life, throw it away. Ready, set, go!
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, millions of times.
どうしたってさ、頭ん中空っぽなこと
After all, the inside of your head is empty.
わかっていないようだ
And it seems you don't understand that.
承認欲にレイプされ、死んだ花をぶら下げている女
A woman hanging dead flowers, raped by her need for approval.
何かを愛することすら、ままならないまま餌を待つだけ
Even without having anything to love, she just waits for her bait.
踊り方を知らない、芸術の価値などわからない奴らに
For those who don't know how to dance and don't value art,
堕落していれば 何も見えないまま
if you fall into depravity, you'll remain seeing nothing.
真善美に背いた踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you a dance that goes against truth, goodness, and beauty,
いっせーので狂っちまえ、惨めな姿で
so just go crazy with ready, set, go! In your miserable state.
何十何百何千何万何億人の中でさ
Out of tens, hundreds, thousands, millions, billions of people,
そうして埋もれていたっていいと
that it is okay to be buried like that,
どうして言えるのだろう
how can you say that?
ねえ、世界が患っている狂信は
Hey, the fanaticism that afflicts this world
健常者でさえ目が眩むような光を放っている
releases a light that leaves even healthy people dizzy.
今夜、悪魔がお前らにこう言うぜ
Tonight, the devil says to you,
「神とやらに惑わされるなよ」
"Do not be fooled by god."
はーい！
Hi!
「悪魔の踊り方」、歌わせていただきました。
I just sang "How to Dance with the Devil"!
いやー、「悪魔の踊り方」ってさ、すごいカッコいい曲じゃない？
Man, "How to Dance with the Devil" is such a cool song, isn't it?
ああいうカッコいい歌歌うと、なんかちゃんと様になっているのかなって
When I sing such a cool song, I wonder if I actually look the part...
なんか心細い気持ちに実はなってるんだよね。
...and I actually end up feeling quite insecure.
ちゃんとカッコよく歌えてたかな？僕。
Did I manage to sing it coolly?
はい。ということでね、なんかもお、ここまで、あっという間だったよね。
Yes! Anyway, it really went by in the blink of an eye, didn't it?
もうこんな時間経ってるんだっていう感じでございますが。
It feels like, "Wow, has it really been this long already?"
なんとですね、ここから、告知タイムと、させていただき...
And believe it or not, from here, we will move on to announcement time...
はい、ということで！
Yes, so!
まずはみんなに見ていただきたいCMがございます！
First, there's a commercial I'd love for all of you to watch!
ああ、やばい。みんな、心して？
Oh, wow. Everyone, brace yourselves.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
ここからは檜山修之が、
From here on, Nobuyuki Hiyama...
猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2026のご紹介をするぞ！まずはこれだ！
will introduce Nekomata Okayu's Birthday Celebration Goods 2026! First up, this!
はっぴ～おかゆはっぴ！
Happy Okayu Happi!
神岡ちろる先生の描き下ろしイラストが描かれた法被がグッズになったぞ！
A happi coat featuring a newly drawn illustration by Kamioka Chirol-sensei is now merch!
きょとん顔のおかゆんがとてもキュート！
Okayun with a puzzled face is super cute!
イベントやライブに着ていけば、一目で「おにぎりゃー」アピールできる、スーパーハッピーなグッズだ！
Wear it to events and concerts to show off that you're an "Onigiri-ya" at a glance! A super-happy item!
お出かけに連れてって！アクリルスタンド！
Take her on your outings! Acrylic Stand!
アクスタはもう家に飾るだけの時代じゃない！日々の「お出かけ」を彩る、推し活マストアイテム！
Acrylic stands aren't just for decorating your home anymore! A must-have "oshi-katsu" item to brighten your daily outings!
ポーチに入れて外に持ち運んで、おかゆんに世界をたくさん見せてあげてくれよな！
Put it in a pouch and take it outside to show Okayun lots of the world!
ごくごく！BIGたんぶらー！
Gulp gulp! Big Tumbler!
甘城なつき先生描き下ろしのミニキャラが描かれた大容量のタンブラー！
A large-capacity tumbler featuring a mini-character drawn by Amashiro Natsuki-sensei!
持ち手やストローもついているので、外出時はもちろん、勉強中や仕事中、
It comes with a handle and straw, so whether you're heading out, studying, or working,
様々なシチュエーションで大活躍間違いなし！
it'll surely be highly useful in various situations!
おかゆんの配信を見るときにも使ってくれ！
Use it when you're watching Okayun's streams too!
おでかけおにぎり型ショルダーポーチ！
Outing Onigiri-Shaped Shoulder Pouch!
アクスタやhololive friends with uなど、ちょっとした小物が入る優れたショルダーポーチだぜ！
An excellent shoulder pouch that can hold small items like acrylic stands or "hololive friends with u"!
透明素材なので、日々の推し活に使える一品となっているぞ！
With its transparent material, it's a great item for your daily "oshi-katsu"!
そして、
And...
フルセット購入特典はこちら！
here is the Full Set Purchase Bonus!
なんとフルセットを購入した全員に、猫又おかゆの直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてくる！
Unbelievably, everyone who purchases the Full Set will receive a postcard with Nekomata Okayu's hand-signed autograph and copy message!
おにぎりゃーの皆、絶対ゲットしてくれよな！
Every Onigiri-ya, make sure to get yours!
やばい！はあー、
Oh my god! Phew...
ということで、あの、
So... well,
檜山修之さんに生誕グッズのCMを撮っていただきました！やばい！
Nobuyuki Hiyama-san recorded the commercial for my birthday goods! Unbelievable!
檜山修之さんというね、あのレジェンドの声優さんがいらっしゃいまして、
Nobuyuki Hiyama-san, who is a legendary voice actor...
猫又おかゆ、ホロライブデビュー時からの、世界で一番大好きな声優さんとなっております。
has been Nekomata Okayu's most favorite voice actor in the entire world since my Hololive debut.
この場をお借りして、檜山修之さん、本当にありがとうございました！
I'd like to take this opportunity to say: Hiyama Nobuyuki-san, thank you so very much!
ちょっと興奮冷めやらぬ、なんですが、あの、
I'm still a bit too excited, but, well...
CMにあった通り、猫又おかゆ生誕グッズ2026を発売させていただきますので、
as shown in the commercial, Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration Goods 2026 are now on sale!
皆さんぜひご予約お待ちしてます！
Everyone, I'm really looking forward to your pre-orders!
そして、告知は1つだけじゃないんですね！
Also, that's not the only announcement!
続きましてこちら！どうぞ！
Next up, here is this! Here you go!
いよいよお待たせかね！来月3月26日、木曜日に、おかゆむーす！R！
Sorry to keep you waiting! Next month, on Thursday, March 26th, "Okayuuum! R"...
R！
...R...
「おかゆむーす！R」がリリース！
..."Okayuuum! R" will be released!
青森を舞台に、君と2人で商品開発という名の恋人旅行がスタート！
Set in Aomori, a couples' trip under the guise of "product development" with you begins!
笑いあり、デートあり、野球拳もあり！
There'll be laughter, dates, and even "yakyuuken" (strip rock-paper-scissors)!
の盛りだくさんの作品となっております。
It's a game packed with so many things.
自分自身で、野球拳ありって何って思っちゃったね。
Even I thought, "What do you mean, 'yakyuuken included'?"
自分自身で言ったくせにね。
Even though I was the one who said it.
僕が、野球拳やりたいって言ったくせにね。
Even though I was the one who said I wanted to play "yakyuuken."
そして、野球拳あるのに、CERO Cで大丈夫なのかよというお声を、度々いただいておりますが、
And I've frequently heard concerns like, "Is a CERO C rating okay despite having yakyuuken?"
なんと心配していたCERO Cさんにも無事、「C」で決まりました！
But amazingly, the CERO C rating we worried about was successfully approved as "C"!
よかった、よかった。
Thank goodness, that's great.
そして、みんな体験版ももう既に遊んでくれたかな？
Also, has everyone played the demo version already?
あのドキドキの続きは、ぜひ君の目で確かめてほしいな！
I hope you'll experience the continuation of that heart-pounding story with your own eyes!
まだまだたくさんの未公開情報もあるとのことなので、
I heard there's still a lot of unrevealed information,
「おかゆむーす！R」から目が離せないよ！
so keep your eyes on "Okayuuum! R"!
ぜひお楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
そしてこちら、最後の告知となります。
And here is the final announcement.
毎年発表させていただいているんですが、今日もライブの最後に新曲を発表させていただきます！
I announce this every year, but today, at the end of the live stream, I will announce a new song!
やっと言えた。
I could finally say it.
今回はですね、てにをはさんに作詞作曲をしていただきました。
For this song, Teniwoha-san wrote the lyrics and composed the music.
ありがとうございました、てにをはさん。
Thank you very much, Teniwoha-san.
でわでわ
Well then...
あの、色々言いたいこととかもあるんですが...
Well, there are many things I want to say...
まずは、君の目でしっかりと聞いていただければなと、見ていただければなと思っております。
But first, I hope you'll listen closely... rather, watch closely with your own eyes.
でわでわ
So then...
聴いてください
Please listen.
ノンデリシャス
Non-Delicious.
今日も噛む噛む ワンツースリー
Chewing, chewing again today, 1, 2, 3
舌も踊るよ ワンツースリー
My tongue is dancing too, 1, 2, 3
トラウマをじっくり煮込んだボルシチどうぞ
Here is some borscht simmered with trauma
キミの心臓は歯型だらけさ
Your heart is covered in bite marks
Come come
苦肉のステーキとセルフィッシュ＆チップス
A desperate steak and selfish & chips
マンネリを刻んだサラダ
A salad tossed with routine
こんなにもおいしい食卓 邪魔しないで
Please don't disturb this delicious dining table
お口を開けて
Open your mouth
はい あーん
Say "ah"
ウェイター！ウェイター！
Waiter! Waiter!
お皿を下げないで
Don't clear the plates
これがボクの「おいしいモノ」なんだから
Because this is my delicious meal
ハングリー ロンリー グラトニー 新しいメニュー
Hungry, Lonely, Gluttony, a new menu
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, what you've been waiting for
デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル・テーブル蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away that terrible table
エブリーデイ エブリーナイト がっつかないで
Every day, every night, don't be greedy
ノンデリシャス
Non-delicious
なんべんだっておかわり
As many servings as you want
おえっ
Ugh...
お皿積み上げ スリーフォーファイブ
Stack up the plates, 3, 4, 5
バベルみたいに スリーフォーファイブ
Like the Tower of Babel, 3, 4, 5
喉の奥につっかえて窒息しかけても
Even if it gets stuck in my throat and I almost choke
大人は飲み込むらしい すっごいね
It seems adults just swallow it down, amazing
二枚舌のソテー 義理人情サンドイッチ
Sautéed double tongue, a duty and humanity sandwich
情熱の冷めたスープ
A soup where passion has cooled down
そんなもの頼んでないから
Because I didn't order such a thing
ボクはボクで好きなものだけ食べるだけ
I will just eat only what I like in my own way
飢え
Hunger!
ウェタウェタ 際限なく持ってきて
Waiter, waiter, keep bringing it endlessly
これがボクの「おいしい日々」なんだから
Because these are my delicious days
異論反論諸々 飲み込んだあとで
After swallowing objections, refutations, and everything else
挑め ダイエット ダイエット
Take on the diet, diet
一心不乱に噛む噛む
Chewing, chewing singlemindedly
不条理を噛む
Chewing on absurdity
のらりくらり 幸せそうな顔して
Aimlessly, put on a happy face
噛む噛む あくまで噛む
Chewing, chewing, chewing to the end
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, what you've been waiting for
デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル・テーブル蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away that terrible table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないて
Every day, every night, don't be greedy
ノンデリシャス
Non-delicious
でも なんべんだっておかわりしよう
But let's have as many servings as we want
はぁ
Phew...
おにぎりゃー！！今日はお祝いしてくれてほんとにありがとう〜〜！！！
Onigiryas! Thank you so much for celebrating with me today!
毎日がハッピーなのも、みんなのおかげ♡ ず〜っと一緒にいたいね。
I'm happy every day thanks to everyone ♡ I want to be with you forever.
ちょっとでも、君の笑顔のきっかけになれますように... 猫又おかゆ
I hope I can be a reason for you to smile, even just a little... - Nekomata Okayu